

PROFILE

I am a 19-year-old student from Kashmir. I became one of the youngest technocrats from the valley, at an age of 14. I am a recipient of Digital India Award, and published my first android app on Google Play in 2014. I have a good knowledge of web development, and graphics designing and prototyping. I am also a published researcher with six journal articles, and one conference paper. I am an avid learner, and my primary interest is in AI, and Public Health. I have many opensource Al projects.

I want to contribute to this world using Artificial Intelligence, by solving global issues that we face every day.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-7006-250-627

WEBSITE:

https://danishshakeel.me

EMAIL:

hi@danishshakeel.me danishshakeel54@gmail.com

PROFILE LINKS

LinkedIn /danishshakeel

ResearchGate /profile/Danish Shakeel3

GitHub /danish17

DANISH SHAKEEL

RESEARCH | DATA SCIENCE | AI | DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT



ttps://danishshakeel.me

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING | CHANDIGARH UNIVERSITY 2018 - 2022

Currently pursuing BE in Computer Science Engineering (spec. in Information Security) from Chandigarh University, Punjab. GPA: 3.7/4

HSE (10+2) | CENTRAL BOARD OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (CBSE) 2017 - 2018

Graduated from High School (10+2) through the Central Board of Secondary Education with a score of 434/500, GPA: 4.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FLICKHIRE DUBAI | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

August 2019–October 2019

To plan, design, develop, and deploy the website.

EZESKOOL DUBAI | IT INTERN (TECH AND PRODUCT)

June 2019-August 2019

To research similar platforms, systematically plan, design, and develop the website, deploy the website, and administrate it.

PUBLICATIONS

PERSONALIZED DRUG CONCENTRATION PREDICTIONS WITH MACHINE **LEARNING: AN EXPLORATORY STUDY**

International Journal of Basic & Clinical Pharmacology Accepted: March 13, 2020

INSECT DETECTION AND FLIGHT TRACKING IN A CONTROLLED ENVIRONMENT USING MACHINE VISION: REVIEW OF EXISTING TECHNIQUES AND AN IMPROVED APPROACH

Elsevier SSRN | 1st Int'l Conference of Intelligent Communication and Computational Research January 25, 2020

THE IMPACT OF INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES (ICTS) ON ACADEMIC PERFORMANCE OF MEDICAL STUDENTS: AN EXPLORATORY **STUDY**

International Journal of Research in Medical Sciences March, 2019

SKILLS

Research and Development Data Science Machine Learning Statistics and Analytics **SQL** Databases Programming Web Development Graphics Designing Prototyping Data Management Content Writing Cloud Services Statistical Programming Android Platform Software Versioning with Git Wordpress Development

Creative Thinking
Problem Solving
Algorithms

Debugging

TOOLS AND LANGUAGES

C C++

Java

Python HTML

CSS

JS

MySQL

MariaDB

Jupyter Notebooks

IBM Watson Studio

Google Cloud Platform

GitHub

Bash

SKLearn

Keras and TF

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe XD

Microsoft Office

Heroku

ADB

Linux

WindowsNT

Wordpress

SPSS

Tableau

TEST SCORES

AMCAT Score: 3453

PUBLICATIONS (CONTINUED)

DOCTORS' SELF-PRESCRIBING BEHAVIOR: AN EXPLORATORY STUDY

International Journal of Research in Medical Sciences February, 2020

COMPARATIVE ASSESSMENT OF ANTIBIOTIC SELF-MEDICATION PRACTICES AMONG UNDER-GRADUATE MEDICAL STUDENTS AND GENERAL POPULATION

International Journal of Research in Medical Sciences December, 2019

ASSESSMENT OF MEDICATION ADHERENCE AMONG PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC DISEASES: A DESCRIPTIVE CROSS-SECTIONAL STUDY

International Journal of Basic and Clinical Pharmacology December, 2018

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

NOTABLE AWARDS:

Digital India Cyber Security Champion

Issued by the Government of India

1st Rank, Int'l Cyber Olympiad

Issued by EduHeal Foundation

3rd Rank, Int'l Science Olympiad

Issued by EduHeal Foundation

1st Rank, National Science Exhibition

Issued by Kendriya Vidyalaya Sangathan

Research Presenter

Issued by ICCR, MRSPTU Punjab

CERTIFICATES:

IBM Advanced Data Science Specialization

Issued by IBM via Coursera

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Issued by IBM via Coursera

GCP For Machine Learning and Big Data

Issued by Google via Coursera

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Issued by Google

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Issued by Google

Digital Skills: Al

Issued by Accenture via FutureLearn

AWS Data Science Elements and DB Migration

Issued by AWS

Web Development Using HTML

SBS Infosystems

HOBBIES

Football
Books
Philosophy
Poetry
Sketching
Trekking
Science
Learning new things
Finding the reason why...

PROJECTS AND APPS

LITMUS AI WEB

An open-source fake news detection web app, which uses a custom-built model, and algorithm. Backend written in Python as a Flask microweb service, frontend using HTML, CSS, JS. Machine learning models created using Scikit Learn, Keras, and Tensorflow, and deployed using Heroku and TFLite.

GitHub: https://github.com/danish17/litmus-ai-web
Website: https://litmus-ai-web.herokuapp.com

DRUG ADMINISTRATION ML

An open-source narrow safety margin personalized drug administration tool, deployed as a webapp. Written in Python, HTML, CSS, JS, machine learning model created using Scikit Learn, and deployed using Heroku.

GitHub: https://github.com/danish17/drug-administration-ml
Website: https://drug-administration-ml.herokuapp.com

INDIAN USED CAR PRICES PREDICTION USING ENSEMBLE LEARNING

An Indian used cars price prediction project, written in Python, HTML, CSS, JS. Machine Learning model created using Scikit Learn.

GitHub: https://aithub.com/danish17/used-car-prices-india

TEXT CORRECTION USING LEVENSHTEIN DISTANCE

A simple command-line app to correct misspelt words. Written completely in C.

GitHub: https://github.com/danish17/levenshtein in c

MY KASHMIR ANDROID APP

An informative app which aims to bring diverse content related to Kashmir, under one roof.

PlayStore: https://tinyurl.com/mykashmirapp